Seán Finnegan

+353 87 381 6890 · sean2001finnegan@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/sean-finnegan-/ Galway, Ireland

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Associate Software Engineer with full-stack training, currently working as a Cloud Engineer at Fidelity Investments. B.Eng (Hons) in Electronic and Computer Engineering from the University of Galway. Previous startup experience solving problems in the fintech and edtech spaces.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Engineer (January 2024 - PRESENT)

Fidelity Investments (Galway/ Hybrid)

Fidelity Investment's are a global leader in financial services. I joined Fidelity's graduate programme as a Full-Stack Engineer after previosuly completing a summer internship.

- Trained as a full-stack engineer on Fidelity's LEAP graduate programme (4 months) the training technology stack included Angular.js, CSS/HTML, Node.js, Spring, OracleDB
- Joined the Cloud team where I am currently working on deploying databases for our customers using Terraform, Helm, Jenkins and AWS.

Skills: AWS · Terraform · Angular.js · MySQL · AerospikeDB · Neo4J · Jenkins · Docker · WSL · Git · Agile

Software Engineer (September 2023 - January 2024)

Breakthrough Maths (Galway/ Hybrid)

Breakthrough Maths is an Irish edtech growth startup striving to deliver high-impact maths classes at scale. I worked on this constantly iterating product as a Cloud and DevOps Engineer

- Worked with load and API testing tools like Artillery and Postman to establish performance baselines under the guidance of an experienced CTO
- Used Terraform Kubernetes to deploy and maintain the devlopment environment.

Skills: AWS \cdot Terraform \cdot PostgresSQL \cdot Kubernetes \cdot Docker \cdot Artillery \cdot Git \cdot QA Testing \cdot User interviews

EDUCATION

University of Galway (2019 - 2023) BEng (Honours)

Electronic and Computer Engineering

- 2.2 overall degree
- 1.1 in dissertation on "Automating expense uploading through the use of APIs"
- National Winner of Fidelity International "Fintech for Good" University Challenge (2019)
- Irish Independent's 30 Under 30 (2021)

JMS Enniscrone (2013 - 2019)

Ranked Top 5.6% in Leaving Certificate 2019

- Top of Class Awards in English, French and Business
- · Connacht Final for Schools Rugby